Fernando Ramallo

Visual Artist / Creative Coder / Technical Artist

fernando.ramallo@gmail.com 213-519-1411 PO BOX 380599 Brooklyn, NY, 11238 www.byfernando.com

ABOUT

I'm an Argentine-born designer and maker. Always tinkering with abstract graphics, generative visuals and strange interactive installations, I'm interested in creating novel, intuitive interfaces for audiovisual experiences.

I've lived in Argentina, Mexico and Berlin while working as a digital nomad on independent projects. I currently live with my partner Kevin in New York City.

SKILLS

- General programming (Unity 3D + C#, Javascript, AS3, Python)
- Gameplay & UI design and programming
- Basic shader programming
- · Unity Editor Tools
- Graphic Design & Art Direction (Adobe suite)
- Polish (Particles, tweening, attention to detail)
- 3D modeling and basic animation (3DS Max, Blender)
- 2D animation & video editing (Adobe Premiere, After Effects)
- · GIT & Subversion Version Control

EXPERIENCE

Technical Artist with Tilt Brush Team at Google (2017)

Tilt Brush is a Virtual Reality application developed by Google for drawing and sketching in 3D space. I joined the team to prototype new interactions and worked on an <u>open-source toolset</u> for importing people's drawing into the game creation tool Unity to turn their drawing into videogames, stories and animations.

VR Prototypes for the HTC Vive (2016)

Prototyped new interfaces in room-scale VR for experiential audiovisual experiences.

- PANORAMICAL VR, manipulating orbs and affecting the environment and music around the player. [Video]
- IMPOSSIBLE SCULPTOR, about creating sculptures, surfaces and spaces using signed distance functions where complex mathematical 3D shapes can be easily manipulated with an intuitive, playful room-scale interface.

Procedural Water Effects, for Wheels Of Aurelia (2016)

Technical Artist

Created a Foam and Shore water effect inside a vertex shader with an intuitive Unity interface for tweaking the parameters.

Trigger-based Tools for Visual Programming inside the Unity Editor, for *Oikosludi* (2016)

UI and Tools Designer, Programmer

Created a customized suite of tools for visual programming that complement the Unity Editor to allow composer David Kanaga to create an entire game without code.

- Simple workflow of placing Triggers in 3D space and determining actions using a visual interface (e.g. play a sound, move an object).
- Multiple ways to control audio effects with player-controlled parameters.
- Intuitive, context-aware UI that changes depending on the selections with helpful tooltips and warnings.

PANORAMICAL (2012-2016)

Co-creator, Lead Designer, Artist and Programmer.

Fact Sheet Trailer Website

My biggest project to date, PANORAMICAL is a collection of interactive abstract musical landscapes, released on PC & Mac in August 2015.

I oversaw the entire production, prototyped and produced intuitive interfaces for multiple devices (including MIDI controllers), implemented easy-to-use tools to facilitate improvisational feel-based content creation, worked with guest artists to create special content, designed press material, and programmed the game's functionality to work cross-platform.

Showcased at 40+ museums, festivals and events around the world, including the **SF MoMA**, **SIGGRAPH**, the **EMP Museum**, and the **Independent Games Festival**.

- Nominated for Grand Prize at AMAZE 2013, Berlin, Germany
- Nominated for Best Audio, Nuovo Award and Best Visual Design, Independent Games
 Festival at the Games Developers Conference 2016, San Francisco, CA
- Winner of Best Sound Design, AZPlay Festival 2015, Bilbao, Spain

Weirdkids Collective, Berlin (2014)

I participated as half of the Berlin-based *art-collective-slash-twitter-joke* **Weirdkids** focusing on abstract interactive places and upcoming noise creators.

I helped curate multiple showcases of digital creators' strange trance-inducing installations taking place at the derelict boiler room of a riverside industrial club.

Independent Game Designer (2010-PRESENT)

Game and UI Designer, Programmer

Worked independently, creating several small projects and prototypes and experimenting with new game mechanics and interfaces.

I attended and showcased work in multiple festivals and independent game events around the world and self-published several games:

- *Dependant* (Design, Programming), a sliding puzzle game.
- Cardboard Box Assembler, (Art, UI) a puzzle game about box-shaped worlds, for Adult Swim
 Games
- Snaaaaake!, (Design, Art, Programming, UI) an arcade game about being a giant snake, for Adult Swim Games

QB9 Games (2008-2010)

Game Designer

Worked as a Game Designer, involved in over 18 published game projects for PC, Web and Consoles. My roles included generating pitches and Design Documents, developing prototypes, creating tools and scripts (Python) to simplify production and balancing difficulty and scores.

Freelance Designer (2004-2008)

Worked as a freelancer offering graphic design, illustration, web design, 2D and 3D animation services to multiple companies and studios in Buenos Aires, Argentina.

SPEAKER EXPERIENCE

- Panelist on Musical Manipulation in videogames, Killscreen Festival 2016, New York, NY
- "Discovering the audiochromatic cosmology of PANORAMICAL", SIGGRAPH 2015, Los Angeles, CA
- "Playful Tools For Abstract Worlds: Creating PANORAMICAL", Indiecade East 2016, New York, NY
- Workshop on basic shaders and prototyping in Shadertoy.com, Screenshake 2015, Antwerp, Belgium
- · Guest speaker, Prof. Richard Lemarchand's class, USC School of Cinematic Arts, Los Angeles, CA
- Guest speaker, Prof. Toni Pizza's class, NYU Game Center, New York, NY
- · Guest speaker, Prof. Coleen Macklin's class, Parsons School Of Design, New York, NY

EDUCATION

Universidad de Palermo, Buenos Aires, Argentina

Audiovisual Designer Degree (Bachelor's equivalent), 2009.